HDFC ARO Optima Secure and ICICI LBA
David are both top health insurance
plans in the industry. If you are confused about
which plan is more suitable for you, then
in this video we will do a
detailed comparison of both these plans on the basis of all their features, benefits,
claim ratios and
premium and in the end we will
try to decide
which plan will be more suitable for you.  So
stay with this video till the end.  Hello
friends, I am Ashutosh, your personal
finance coach.  Let's start the video.
HDFC ARGO Optima Secure and ICICI
LBD Elevate are both highly recommended plans by advisors.
So let us
now compare both these plans to see
which one can be the best.
Talking about Optima Secure and ICICI LBA Elevate minimum and maximum entry age, both the plans have a minimum of 18 years
and no maximum entry age limit.  You can
enter at any age.
Senior citizens can also take it.   The
age limit for a dependent child is usually 90 days.
Any health insurance plan
covers newborn babies after 90 days.
Sum insured options are Rs
5 lakh to 2CR in HDFC and Optima Secure.  ICICI LBAD
Elevate has 5 lakh to 3cr.  Apart from this,
another important option that we get in Elevate is
Unlimited Sum Assured.  This
is the biggest advantage of this plan, Unlimited Sum
Assured.  So there will be no limit on the coverage of sum assured.
Room Category There is no
category wise capping in HDFC Ergo Optima Secure.  You
can take any category of room.  ICICI LBA Elevate has a
capping of inbuilt single private AC room.
But you can remove it with a rider room modifier.
AYUSH treatments or
alternative treatments like
Ayurvedic, Unani, Siddha, Homeopathy are
covered up to the sum assured in both the plans. Pre & Post Hospitalization
HDFC Optima Secure 60 Days & 180 Days.
Whereas ICICI Lob 90 Days and 180 Days.  This can be a
very important benefit
during pre and post
hospitalization when we make a claim.  So
we need a plan that
covers them for maximum number of days.  Day care
treatments are treatments that do not require 24-hour
hospitalization.  But still,
due to technological advancement,
this can be done in a few hours procedure.  So
all day care
treatments are covered in both the plans.  Organ donor cover
is covered up to sum assured in both the plans.  Domiciliary hospitalization
is covered up to sum assured in both the plans.
Domestic hospitalizations are
hospitalizations that we
take in our homes.  So if
beds are not available in the outside hospital or the patient
cannot be taken to the hospital, then we
take domestic hospitalization.  Home
care treatment.  Home care treatment is covered
at S per actuals in HDFC Ergo Optima Secure.
In ICIC LBAD Elevate
we get Nursing at Home option which
covers for some limited discs.  So
for home care treatment, HDFC Ergo
option is better.  Road Ambulance
is covered up to sum assured in both the plans.  There is no capping.  Air
Ambulance HDFC Ago Optima Secure has
inbuilt cover up to Rs 5 lakh.
In ICICI LBD Elevate we have to take Edge add on.
Free health checkup once in a policy year
covered in HDFC Ergo Optima Secure
Inbuilt ICICI LBAD Elevate we have to
take it as an add on.  Modern treatments
are covered up to sum assured in both the plans.  For modern treatments, we should keep in
mind that
most insurance companies do
not cover modern treatments if traditional treatments are available for those treatments.  So
even though there is no capping on modern treatment, there is a hidden clause in it
that insurance companies
give more preference to traditional treatment.
Second medical opinion
is available once per person.  ICICI is not in LBAV.  E-
Consultation is inbuilt in HDFCO Optima Secure.
ICIC LBD
is available as an add-on in Elevate.  We get maternity cover
in both the plans.  A
waiting period of 2 years is available for maternity in both the plans.
Whereas in HDFCO Optima
Secure, maternity benefits ranging from Rs 50 lakh to Rs 2 lakh are
available.  Whereas
in Elevate, benefits up to 10% of sum insured maximum
up to Rs 1 lakh will be available.
Also, HDFC R Optima Secure does
not cover newborn babies.  But
Elevate has a newborn baby cover which is a
part of the maternity cover.  Twice the
maternity cover is a newborn baby cover.
However, on the basis of premiums, I would
not recommend both these plans.
Maternity becomes quite expensive.
We get options for worldwide cover
in both the plans.  Whereas
Optima Secure Global
and Optima Secure Global Plus variants
are available in HDFC Ergo.  The Global variant
covers only emergency hospitalization
outside India and Global Plus
also covers plant hospitalization.
However, these options are definitely a bit expensive.
According to the normal borders which are covered worldwide.
In ICICI lambda Deliver also we get world wide
cover as an add on for plant
hospitalization and also
for emergency hospitalization. Plan variants:
In HDFC R Optima Secure we get four
variants Optima
Secure which is normal and Optima Super
Secure which if we pay 3 years premium together
then we get Super Secure
option which gives us 1x
more coverage, meaning normally in this plan
we get 2x coverage from day one but if we
pay 3 years premium then in
addition to 3x coverage, Optima
Secure Global also covers emergency hospitalization.
Optima Secure
Global Plus covers plant hospitalization
outside India.  Elevate has only
one variant in which we get
to see a lot of addons.  Waiting
Periods Normal: Like all plants, there is an
initial waiting period of 30 days.
Specific waiting period of two years for specific
diseases which are slow growing diseases.
They have an inbuilt waiting period of 2 years.
Apart from this, there is a 3-year pre-
existing disease waiting period
in both the plans.  Talking about the unique benefits of these plans, first of all,
in HDFC Ergo Optima Secure, we
get Secure Benefit which doubles our coverage from Day One.
So if we
take a policy of Rs 10 lakh, it immediately
covers for Rs 20 lakh.  And if we
take the Super Secure option by paying the premium for 3 years,
we get an additional benefit of 2x.
Meaning you already have 1x coverage
and 2x additional.  So you get this 3x policy
from day one.  Apart from that, we
get the Plus benefit inbuilt which is a
cumulative bonus which gives you a bonus of 50%,
50-50% for the next two years,
maximum up to 100% bonus.
Apart from that, you get the benefit of unlimited restoration.
Although this
is optional, its cost is quite low.  Apart from this,
Protect Benefit which provides
inbuilt cover for non-payable items.  You do
not need to take a separate rider.  The next
rider is Limitless.  This was launched last year
in 2025 in which you
get the option of infinite sum assured.  If your
policy is less than Rs 50 lakh, then there are claim options of Once in a
Lifetime and if it is more than Rs 50 lakh, then there are Twice in a
Lifetime claim options in
which there will be no limit on the sum assured.
So you have a policy of Rs 10 lakh,
secure benefit of Rs 2030 lakh and plus
benefit.  Even after that, if a claim
of Rs 90 lakh comes, then you can exercise this option as an
add-on.  Apart from that we
get ABCD cover for lifestyle diseases.  This means that for hypertension, blood pressure,
asthma and cholesterol, the
three-year waiting period for normal pre-existing conditions gets
waived off
and they are covered in 31 days only.
Talking about the unique benefits of ICICI LBA, the
most important one is Power Booster in which we
get 100% bonus every year.  So if your
policy is worth Rs 10 lakh, then you will
get a cumulative bonus of Rs 10 lakh every year.
Apart from that, there is also an inbuilt bonus of 20% which will be
available up to a maximum of 100%.
Apart from that, there is an option of Infinite Care
which is similar to HDFC Ergo's Limitless
which gives you a claim for unlimited amount once in a policy lifetime.
Apart from that, unlimited restoration
full and partial unlimited time.  So earlier there was
a capping of 45 days for the same person with the same illness, which was later removed by the company.
This was the only
drawback in this plan which the company has
now removed.  Apart from that, Jump Start
which is like ABCD cover which is
hypertension, diabetes, asthma,
hyperlipidemia.  Apart from that, if
your BMI is very high then these people cover up to 39.
Apart from this,
if you have coronary artery disease i.e. PTC
or stent insertion before one year, then also
you can get covered with this rider without any waiting
period.  It is a very good option.
Apart from two-hour hospitalization,
normally health insurance plans cover 24 hours
hospitalization.  But this
plan also covers two-hour hospitalization
with this add-on.  But if there is a condition then there should be an
active line of treatment.   It should
not be for observatory purposes.
Talking about optional benefits, HDFC Ergo
Optima Secure offers an NRI
discount of up to 40%. If you
are an NRI, this plan can be very good for you.  Apart from that,
Unlimited
Restoration Critical Illness Cover.  So this
critical illness is a fixed benefit
in which the insurance company gives you cash of Rs 5 lakh, Rs 10 lakh or whatever
your sum insured is.  You
don't get it in cash in your account
but you get it in lump sum.  Your
health insurance policy covers all critical
illnesses.  But that is indemnity
cover.  Covers hospitalization.
So, if you need cover for out-of-pocket expenses,
this critical illness rider comes in handy.
However, we should
take a separate critical illness policy.  Should
not be taken with health insurance.
Hospital Daily Cash:
If you need it for out-of-pocket expenses during hospitalization, you can
opt for this rider.
Apart from that, Personal Accident
also gives
you lump sum benefit in case of accidental death or disability due to personal accident.
Weekly
benefits are also provided during disability.  But for that also
I would advise you to
take a separate personal accident policy.
Apart from this, for OPD we get Optima Well
Being rider and deductible
option in which we have the
option of annual aggregate deductible.   There are
options ranging from Rs 25,000 to Rs 5 lakh.  So, if
you find the policy expensive,
you can avail a discount by opting for a deductible.
Talking about the riders of ICIC LBD, there are a
lot of riders in it.  Infinite
Care which lets you claim unlimited amount once in a policy lifetime.
Inflation Protector: This rider
comes in handy when you have not taken Power Booster, that is, you have
not taken the bonus one, then this
Inflation Protector increases the
sum assured of your policy every year according to inflation,
so whatever the CPI
index is, your basic coverage will increase by 5-6%,
Power Booster gives you a bonus of 100% every year,
Domestic Air Ambulance
Jump Start which are ABCDC diseases like
Asthma, Blood Pressure, Cholesterol,
Opacity, Dependent Accommodation is covered without waiting period.
If the hospitalization is more than 10 days,
you get benefits for the accommodation of the dependent.
Claim Protector: This
covers non-payable items.  Like
HDFC Ergo Optima Secure, non-payable
items are inbuilt covers.  In this we have to
take a rider.  Next is the room modifier.
So there is capping of inbuilt single private AC room.
But with this rider you
can remove it.  Apart from this, compassionate
visit.  So, if your hospitalization
is in another city, then compassionate visit means that the
immediate family member gets the
airfare charges for travelling to and fro.  Nursing at
home is useful if any
pre- or post-hospitalization treatment is required at home.
Maternity benefit comes
with a waiting period of two years.  Newborn baby
cover is a part of maternity benefit.
Vaccination of newborn baby is also a
part of maternity benefit.  Durable
Medical Equipment: If
after discharge from the hospital, you need durable medical
equipment like a wheelchair,
either for rent or for purchase, then
you get its benefits in this.  Covalsons
Benefit Health Checkup So is not an inbuilt health
checkup.  You have to pay for that separately.
Bfit This is OPD rider.   If
you need OPD, there are different
sections in it.  You can
select them according to your requirement.
Next is Network
Advantage.  So if we
select the option with network advantage,
we get some discount in our premium.
But our hospitalization gets
restricted and we can get treatment only in
those particulars which are their preferred
network.   If we
go outside the preferred network,
we have to pay a comment.  So we should
ignore it.  We have to take personal accident cover
and criticality cover separately.
Is teleconsultation okay?  It is a good benefit.  Option to
reduce maternity waiting period.  There
is a waiting period of 2 years for maternity.  But you
can also take it for one year with this rider.
However, its maternity and
both these riders are quite expensive.  If
we find the premium high, there
is an option of voluntary copayment.  So what's mostly in Higher Edge
?  When our premium becomes unaffordable,
we can take the policy with co-payment.
NRI discount is up
to 25%.
HDFC Aego Optima Secure has two zones.
ICICI LBA Delivered has four zones.
Talking about the premium, for that
I have taken the example of a 35 year old couple
with two kits
for Rs 10 lakh sum assured in Delhi NCR Zone One.  So the
premium for HDFCO Optim Secure is ₹564.
Whereas ICIC LBD Elevate in which I have
taken Power Booster and Claim Shield.  Its
premium is Rs 20296
and there is another benefit in this that
we also get civil discount.  Talking about multi-year
policy, in multi-year policy
we get multi-year discount
and apart from that we are also saved from inflation
because insurance companies keep
increasing their premium due to inflation.
So in a multi-year policy,
one of us gets this help.
Maximum 3 years
policy is available in HDFC Optima Secure.  In ICICI LBD we
also get a five year policy which is
a very good option.  Let us now
talk about their claim ratios.  So the best measure to see the performance of
any health insurance is the Incurred
Claim Ratio.  HDFCO holds
84.25% of Optima Secure.  Meaning that it is a
very good and healthy ratio.  This means
that if the company is charging a premium of ₹100, then it is
giving you a claim of ₹84.  She is
keeping only ₹15 with herself.  Meaning that it is a
pretty good healthy ratio.  By the way, ICICI
LBD also has an unclaimed claim ratio of 82%.  And if we
look at the record of last five years,
both remain above 7075.  So,
one thing we can know from the incurred claim ratio is
that both the companies are good in terms of paying claims.  The
claim settlement ratio
of HDFC Ago is 93%.  Whereas ICICI holds
80.98% of LBR.  This means that the claim settlement ratio
is low but the incurred claim ratio is quite high.
Talking about the complaint ratio, out of
10,000 claims, it is 15 in HDFC Ago
and 14 in ICICI LBRD.  The meaning
is quite reasonable.  Talking about value for money,
HDFC Ago Optima Secure
is expensive.  ICICI LBD is fair valued.  So
friends, this was about both the plans.
We have seen all the features.  If we
talk about value for money, then
somewhere ICICI LBD seems to us to have more value for
money.  But if we talk about all the claim ratios, then
somewhere or the other HDFC Ago has
that edge.  So if we consider a higher sum assured policy,
then HDFC Ago can be a better
option for us
with policies of Rs 25 lakh, 50 lakh, 1 crore
and if we talk about ICICI LBD, then in this
we get the benefit of power booster
which increases our coverage by 100% every year.
So
if we are looking at a policy of Rs 10-15 lakh then ICICI
Lambar is a better option.  Friends,
as important as health insurance is, it is
equally important to get it from the right place.
After sales service plays
a very important role in health insurance.  So try to
take it from such an advisor who can
help you at the time of your claim.  If you
want to take your health insurance with me, do your financial planning
or you want me to
manage your wealth, then you
can connect with me on the number given below or you can book a paid consultation
with me by visiting my website ahsshukla.com.  That's all for
today's
video, see you
in the next video.  Thank you.